# **Alma Ruth Casaos**

**Architect, Lighting Designer** 

Av. Juarez Poniente # 144 Col. Cuajimalpa Mexico D.F. 05000 01152(55) 39637671

ruthcasaos@gmail.com

**Friday, January 8th, 2016**Personnel, Human Resources
Grupo SYASA

I am very interested in this position with SyASA Company and I believe that my education, experience and employment background are appropriate for this position. I am familiar with all National Lighting brands and International brand products also and I think, there are a good real technical and funtional solutions for the lighting projects in Mexico with high quality and very simple and flexible to use.

I come from a background of 22 years of lighting and control design systems, I have got training in lighting design using software of different Manufactures Companies like Light Gear of Hubbell lighting, Luxicon of Cooper lighting, Cala of Holophane lighting and lighting controls like Vantage controls, Lutron controls, Lightolier Controls, etc.

I have the experience designing Lighting in all kind of bulding and constructions like Residential, Comercial Centers, Offices, Industrial, Hotels etc., and systems through companies representatives of the factory and I have worked managing factory sales people, I have the experience in specifying and working with specifiers of lighting & controls systems such as Consulting Engineers, Electrical Contractors, Architects, distributors and dealers.

I have the experience programming lighting control systems and installing them as well. I have a strong academic background of the Architectural spaces as well as lighting fixtures and use of the different kind of bulbs and control system designs

Enclosed is a copy of my resume, which more fully details my qualifications for the position. I look forward to putting my knowledge and experience in the matter into practice in the future projects in Syasa Company.

I will contact you in this week to see if you require any additional information regarding my qualifications.

Thank you for your consideration.

Sincerely,

Alma Ruth Casaos

# **RESUME:**

**Alma Ruth Casaos** 

**Architect, Lighting Designer** 

Av. Juarez poniente # 144 Col.Cuajimalpa Mexico D.F. Mexico City C.P. 05000 01152(55) 39637671

ruthcasaos@gmail.com

### **Objective:**

To become a valuable and contributing member of the team. Willing always to teach and be taught new and different ways to increase knowledge and ability in achieving any set goal.

I posses 22 years of experience working in lighting design designing with all National and International brands there are in the National Market and development of lighting control systems focus on energy saving and smart-buildings application.

I have built relationships with the most important specifications firms, Hands-on experience designing lighting projects, installing, programming and trouble shouting with products of brands like Hubbell Lighting, Cooper Lighting, Rimmer Lighting, Construlita, Magg, Philips, ventor, etc and Lightolier controls Lutron controls, Vantage controls as well I have been working like Technical support and product specification for companies of design such as Consulting engineers, Electrical Contractors, distributors and dealers in order to develop sale-projects.

# **Education:**

Degree: Architecture July 1990 -1994

Universidad Nacional Autonoma de Mexico UNAM, Mexico City

Architecture College

Thesis: Resort in Cancun, focus on Lighting and control systems.

**BYU: ESL** Provo, Utah

**Seminars:** Training in Lutron Control Systems at Lutron Coopersburg, PA

Training in Lighting Design at Cooper lighting Chicago IL

Training in Lighting Controls at Vantage Controls, Orem UT and

Vantage controls Mexico city.

Training in Lighting design Gear software at Hubbell lighting

Greenville, SC

Training in Rimmer Consulting at LA California and Mexico City

# **Professional Experience:**

(In inverse chronological order)

## **SONOLUZ DEL CARIBE Enterprise.**

Date: April 2015 to present

Position: Manager of Lighting and Control Systems Design

Responsibilities:

Technical support and specification in lighting and control designs of projects around country specially in the Mexican Caribbean developing lighting designs and control Systems specifying products of brands like Magg. Ventor, Construlita, Hadco, Hubbell Lighting, Cooper Lighting, Lithonia, Philips, Hydrel, Lutron Controls and Vantage controls for projects in the Caribbean Area, Cancun Q. Roo and Merida.

Working close with electric engineering designers, architectural designers and interior designers in order to integrate load schedule of lighting and requirements of control according with the activities or duties to develop in the architectural spaces in order to satisfy the customers needs.

## **ROCKETERIAS DISTRIBUIDORE Enterprise.**

Date: April 2012 to 2015

Position: Manager of Lighting and Control Systems Design

Responsibilities:

Technical support and specification in lighting and control designs of projects around country, developing lighting designs and control Systems specifying products of brands like: Magg, Construlita, Ventor, Elation, Raymates, Rimmer Lighting, Lutron Controls and Vantage controls for projects in the Caribbean Area, Cancun Q. Roo and Merida.

Working close with electric engineering designers, architectural designers and interior designers in order to integrate load schedule of lighting and requirements of control according with the activities or duties to develop in the architectural spaces in order to satisfy the customers needs.

## Pycelmec Enterprise.

Date: April 2006 to 2012

Position: Manager of Lighting and Control Systems Design in the Engineering

Tech Department Responsibilities:

Technical support and specification in lighting and control designs of projects around country, developing lighting designs and control Systems specifying products of brands like: Hubbell Lighting, Cooperlighting, Killark, Lithonia, Novalux, LJ, Lutron Controls and Vantage controls for projects in the Mexico City.

Working close with electric engineering designers, architectural designers and interior designers in order to integrate load schedule of lighting and requirements of control according with the activities or duties to develop in the architectural spaces in order to satisfy the customers needs.

#### **Wesco Distributor.**

Date: March 2005 to March 2006

Position: Lighting design Manager and Technical support

Responsibilities:

Technical support and specification in lighting and control products working with brands like Cooper Lighting, Hubbell Lighting, Lutron, Vantage, Lightolier, Litetoutch, Leviton-Wattstopper, in order to support the specification of product in projects for engineering and Architecs firms of design, Electrical Contractors, distributors and dealers such as

(Starco Distributor, GrayBar Electric, Wholesale electrical distributors, etc), in order to develop sale-projects. Working closely in training of lighting and control product, and lighting design of customer projects, and power point presentation with customers, contractor and distributors.

I was involved working with the top lighting and Control Designers Companies in Mexico City at the time. I created power point presentations to train engineers of electric design, developed proposals of solution to specific projects and developed detailed specification of lighting and control design.

#### Starco, Zumtobel Mexico.

Date: February 1998 to January 2005

Position: Technical support, Lighting and Control System support, sales representative

#### Responsibilities:

Technical support and product specification in projects for contractors and distributors, training Sales people on Lutron controls and specification in lighting design using software in order to install and to program Lutron Controls system for final users.

# Transtek L.T.D. Lighting Desing and control consoulting, Luis lozoya Company

Date: January 1993 to December 1997

Position: Technical support in Lighting designs

Responsibilities:

Product specification and lighting design.

I was on charge of developing lighting design by software Dialux and create catalogue of lighting fixtures specification sheets and applications.

#### Other languages:

ESL Bilingual Spanish-English fluently

#### other skills:

Experience with computer- based design AutoCAD,

Proficient in Excel, Word, Power point, all Microsoft aspects.

Proficient in lighting & control design by software of different manufactures companies of lighting and control products,( Cala of Holophane, Luxicon of Cooper, Dialux, Cophos of Zumtobel, Gear of Hubbell),

Proficiente in reading blue prints of arcuitectural and electric layouts as well as load schedule and electrical diagrams.

all aspects of internet.